What about...
在那之後...
the others who were at the Saimori house? Were they all okay?
待在齋森家的其他人還好嗎?
They are all fine.
所有人都平安無事
Good.
太好了
You're still worried about them, after everything you went through?
都發生那種事了,妳還擔心他們?
More than anything, I'm so glad you are safe, Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐人沒事真的太好了
Um, how about the house?
請問一下,宅邸怎麼樣了?
Completely burned down.
全都燒毀了
Completely burned down...
竟然全都燒毀了
Sir, I have a favor to ask.
老爺,我有個請求
Will you take me to the Saimori house once again?
能否請你再次帶我去齋森家?
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
我的幸福婚約
EPISODE 7 GLAMOROUS LADY OF SUMMER
第 7 集 劇名:夏花般的淑女
Watch your step.
小心腳下
Okay.
好的
So it's true, it's completely burned to the ground.
真的全都燒成黑炭了
Yeah.
是啊
Having lost their mansion in the fire, Shinichi and Kanoko Saimori
失去宅邸的齋森真一和香乃子
let most of the servants go and are moving to their villa in the countryside.
解僱了大部分的傭人 預計移居到鄉下的別邸
Basically a fall from grace, I guess.
齋森家已經實質上沒落了
Although it's true the Tatsuishi family caused this to happen,
造成沒落的原因無疑是出在辰石家
it's not been made public.
卻沒有對外公開
There will be no legal consequences for the Tatsuishi family.
當家雖不會受到法律制裁
But to take responsibility,
還是得負起責任
their eldest son Kazushi will take over as the head of the Tatsuishi family.
辰石家當家之位交由長子 辰石一志接任
I see.
這樣啊
The new head of the family accepted certain restrictions under my supervision.
新當家同意在我的監視下 行動受到某些限制
In effect, the Tatsuishi family will be under the Kudo family's command.
如此一來,辰石家實際上 就納入了久堂家麾下
Then, what about Kaya?
那香耶呢?
She will be sent alone as a servant to a family known to be very strict.
她會獨自被派到 以非常嚴格聞名的家族工作
It would be good for her to experience the outside world.
讓她吃點苦頭,見見世面比較好
Kaya.
香耶
What is it?
什麼事?
I'm going out for a while.
我出門一下
Are you okay with so few belongings?
只帶那些行李就夠了嗎?
What's that? Are you being sarcastic?
那是什麼意思?你在挖苦我嗎?
Kaya. This is a new start.
香耶,這是一個新的開始
Let's start a new life from here.
我們從頭開始重新來過吧
We'll rebuild the Saimori family together.
一起重振齋森家
You don't want this to be the end, do you?
妳也不想在這裡結束吧?
Don't talk down to me!
少用自以為是的口吻說話!
Weren't you going out?
你不是要出門嗎?
Yeah, I'm going now.
我現在要出去了
That's nice. Good day.
是喔,再見了
This cherry tree was planted on the day my mother got married.
這是母親剛嫁入門時所種的櫻花樹
Is this what you wanted to see?
妳之所以來,是因為想看這棵樹?
Yes.
是的
I felt like my mother was calling me to come here.
總覺得母親呼喚我來這裡
What's the matter?
怎麼了嗎?
Um, nothing.
不,沒事
I think what I did was uncalled-for.
都怪我多此一舉
Sir?
老爺?
I'm partly responsible for the matter becoming as serious as it did.
會釀成那種重大火災我也有責任
That's not true.
沒那回事
What you did for me sir, was not uncalled-for.
老爺為我所做的事情並非多此一舉
Miyo.
美世
You have made me very happy.
我真的非常開心
Are you done here?
已經看夠了嗎?
Yes.
是的
You know,
不過呢
the engagement ceremony may be difficult, given the situation of the Saimori family.
以齋森家現在的狀態 看來是無法舉行訂婚儀式了
The engagement ceremony...
訂婚?
Yeah. It's about our future.
是啊,關於我們倆今後的事
I'm thinking of starting the procedures for us to get married pretty soon.
我想在近期著手辦理結婚手續
We might have to go meet the former head of the family.
過幾天可能會去拜訪前任當家
The former head?
前任當家?
You mean... your father?
是指老爺的父親嗎?
Yeah. He kept pressuring me to look for possible candidates to be my wife.
是啊,他一聽說哪家有 適婚年齡的千金就會派人提親
I was fed up with it.
我一直感到為難
So the marriage offer made to the Saimori family was from your father?
向齋森家提親的也是老爺的父親吧?
I have to be sure not to let him down.
我得努力不讓他失望
Why would he be let down?
為什麼會失望?
The proposal must have been meant for Kaya.
因為他當時提親的對象一定是香耶
If that happens, I'll turn him into charcoal, without question.
若真如此,我一定二話不說 就把前任當家燒成黑炭
Pardon?
什麼?
Koji.
幸次先生
Thank you for the other day, Mr. Kudo.
久堂先生,上次的事很感謝你
Are you recovering well?
身體沒事吧?
Yes, thank you for asking.
託你的福,我沒事
I'm glad.
太好了
Miyo, can I talk to you for a minute?
美世,方便聊一下嗎?
Koji, I'm grateful for what you did for me the other day.
幸次先生,前些日子謝謝你的幫忙
I didn't do anything.
我什麼忙也沒幫上
All I could do was inform Mr. Kudo.
只能找久堂先生過來
No, he said that he was able to rescue me quickly because of you.
不,老爺說多虧有你 他才能及早去救我出來
Is that right?
是那樣啊?
I have decided to leave this town.
我決定離開這座城市
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡?
To the old capital. I want to retrain myself.
我要去舊都重新鍛鍊自己
I realized how much strength I'm lacking.
因為深感自身能力不足
I don't want to be useless anymore.
不想繼續無能為力下去
I'm certain
我覺得啊
that Kaya will do her best where she'll be a servant.
香耶也會在工作的地方好好努力
I'll try my best too.
我也會加油的
I want to be strong so I can protect whom I want when I want.
讓自己變強,強大到在緊要關頭 得以保護想守護之物
And... Remember?
還有啊...
A while ago, when we had a talk, I was about to say something?
妳還記得那天我說到一半的話嗎?
Huh?
什麼?
I'm sorry.
對不起
I wanted to help you.
我曾經想拯救妳
I wanted to be able to laugh with you in a normal way like we used to.
想像以前一樣平凡地跟妳一起歡笑
Because I--
因為我對妳...
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I'm not sure what you're talking about...
我不記得了
I see.
這樣啊
No, it's okay.
不,沒關係
It's nothing important.
不是什麼重要的事
It was good to be able to hear what you had to say.
我一直都很想聽到妳的回答 真是太好了
Well, I guess I should go now.
那我該走了
Miyo, until we meet again.
美世,有緣再會
I’ve got to strive to be better, too.
我也不能認輸
Our engagement procedure was a simple one.
我們的結婚手續很簡單
All we had to do was write our names on the form.
只需在文件上簽名即可
In the end, the engagement ceremony was not held by the two families.
到頭來兩家並沒有舉行訂婚儀式
With our two signatures, I officially became his fiancée.
我們兩個在文件上簽完名後 我正式成為老爺的未婚妻
KIYOKA KUDO MIYO SAIMORI
(久堂清霞 齋森美世)
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
Soon you will formally become Mrs. Kudo.
您很快就會正式成為久堂家的夫人呢
Mrs. Kudo? Oh my...
久堂家的夫人?萬萬不敢
Anybody home?
有人在家嗎?
I'll be right there.
馬上來
Oh, are you Miyo-chan?
哎呀,妳就是美世妹妹嗎?
Y-Yes.
是的
Pleased to meet you. I'm Hazuki Kudo.
幸會啊,我是久堂葉月
I'm Kiyoka's older sister.
是清霞的姊姊
You're saying you want to redo lessons to become a lady?
妳說想要重新接受淑女教育?
Yes. Is it out of the question?
是的,不可以嗎?
No, I have no objection to it.
也不是不可以
But do you have to?
妳非學不可嗎?
Yes. I'll find the teacher myself, and I won't cause you any trouble.
是的,我會自己找老師 也不會給老爺添麻煩
Please.
拜託你了
You don't have to lower your head like that.
妳不用低頭請求我
Your face is red.
妳的臉好紅
Do you have a fever?
是不是發燒了?
It doesn't seem so.
似乎沒發燒
I don't have a fever. I'm fine.
沒有發燒,我很健康
Are you sure?
真的嗎?
Yes, it's just that I... Um...
對,會這樣臉紅因為...那個...
Relax, I'm not teasing you.
別那樣看我
Well, I guess it's all right.
好吧,就順著妳的意思做
Thank you, sir.
老爺
I know someone who could be a teacher.
能擔任老師的人選我心裡有底
I'll invite her over to our house.
下次我會聯絡對方來家裡一趟
Thank you--
謝謝你...
Don't worry about it.
不必跟我客氣
It would just be putting a person of leisure to good use.
我只是充分利用閒人罷了
A person of leisure?
閒人?
Please help yourself.
請用茶
Oh, thank you so much. I was just feeling thirsty.
哎呀,謝謝妳,我正好口渴了
So you are my husband-to-be's older sister.
原來妳是老爺的姊姊啊
Yes. Don't we look alike? People often tell me our eyes are similar.
是啊,我們長得很像吧? 大家常說我眼睛跟清霞很像
Oh, yes. Um...
是的,那個...
Ms. Hazuki.
葉月小姐
It has been a long time.
好久不見了
Oh! Yurie!
天啊!由里江!
It's really been a long time.
真的好久沒見到妳了
How many years has it been since the last time we met?
上次見面是幾年前呢?
I'm glad to see that you're still doing well.
看到妳還這麼有精神,真是太好了
You haven't changed, Ms. Hazuki.
葉月小姐也沒變呢
Good grief. You really haven't changed, Sis.
真是的,姊姊還是老樣子
Oh, Kiyoka. Don't you have to go to work?
哎呀,清霞,你今天不用出勤嗎?
I'm off duty today.
今天休息
Oh, for heaven's sake!
真是的,好討厭喔
You're always so grumpy.
你這個人真的很冷淡耶
Cheer up. You have this cute fiancée now.
虧你好不容易找到這麼可愛的未婚妻
It's none of your business.
少多管閒事
All right, whatever.
算了
Anyway, Miyo-chan. Oh, is it okay if I call you Miyo-chan?
話說美世妹妹... 啊,我可以這麼稱呼妳嗎?
Y-Yes.
當然可以
Did you know I was called here by Kiyoka to give you lessons on how to be a lady?
那麼美世妹妹有聽說我是 受清霞之託,要擔任妳的老師嗎?
Pardon?
什麼?
Uh, Kiyoka. You didn't tell her?
不會吧,清霞,你沒告訴她嗎?
Well, I thought I did.
不,我有提過
I apologize for him. Kiyoka always neglects explanations.
抱歉喔,清霞總是不把話說清楚
I bet he didn't tell you much about me.
反正他一定沒有跟妳好好介紹我的事
Uh, well... um...
不,那個...
It's okay.
沒問題的
I'll take responsibility to make you into a refined lady.
我會負責讓妳成為一名出色的淑女
Th-Thank you for taking me on.
那就請妳多多指教
It's the season of tenjikubotan, isn't it?
已經到了天竺牡丹盛開的季節啊?
You know, tenjikubotan is called "dahlia" in other countries.
“天竺牡丹”的外語叫做“dahlia”
Doesn't it sound lovely?
名字很好聽吧?
I just love these flowers.
我最喜歡這種花了
Come over here, Miyo-chan.
美世妹妹,過來一下
Y-Yes.
好的
Do you have a favorite flower?
美世妹妹有喜歡的花嗎?
Well...
我想想...
I don't know many names of flowers.
我不太懂花名
Ah, those weeds are called Asiatic dayflowers.
那個啊,是名叫鴨跖草的雜草
Do weeds have names too?
雜草也有名字啊?
Of course. No matter how small, all flowers have names.
當然有,再小的花都有自己的名字
And they're all beautiful.
而且都很漂亮
Dayflowers only remain open until around noon.
鴨跖草的花只會開到中午
Still, they stand tall and bloom proudly.
儘管如此,它仍抬頭挺胸 堂堂正正地綻放
You know, I've always felt that all flowers are beautiful
我一直覺得啊
because they try their hardest to bloom for the limited time they have.
正因為花在有限的時間努力綻放 才會顯得如此美麗
Aren't we the same, Miyo-chan?
我們也一樣對吧?美世妹妹
Let's try our best to live beautifully for the limited time we have.
為了在有限的時間活得美麗 一起努力加油吧
Yes.
好的
ENCOURAGEMENT OF HOMEMAKING
(《家庭守則》)
First of all, you want to learn the proper behaviors of a lady, right?
我就開門見山地問了 妳想學習淑女應有的儀態舉止吧?
Yes.
是的
I-I'm ready to learn.
請多指教
Actually, I had an unsuccessful marriage.
我曾有過一段失敗的婚姻
But I graduated from Girls' School, and have taken a ton of lessons.
不過我畢業於女校 也學了很多項才藝
So I can teach you the basics with no problem.
應該能好好教妳基礎的部分
You can take it easy, okay?
妳就輕鬆地學吧
Um, I... I'm so happy that you came.
那個,我真的非常高興
I can't believe my husband-to-be's sister came to give lessons to somebody like me.
老爺的姊姊居然願意教導 這樣的我成為一名出色的淑女
I'm very honored.
我感到非常光榮
That's good!
太好了!
Ooh, she's such a good girl!
天啊,這孩子怎麼這麼乖?
Kiyoka, can I take her back home?
清霞,我可以把她帶回家嗎?
No.
不行
Be generous. She'll learn more if she buckles down and studies with me.
真小氣,帶美世回我家 好好學習更能幫上她吧
No!
不行!
I understand.
我想也是啦
If I took Miyo-chan away from here, you would be lonely without her.
要是我帶走美世妹妹 你一定會很寂寞吧
Th-That's not...
才沒那種事...
Anyway, if you're gonna study, I think you need some kind of goal.
總之呢,要學習的話 最好還是要有個目標
A goal?
目標嗎?
Yes. If you have a tentative goal, you can work towards it.
沒錯,姑且有個目標後 就能朝著達成好好努力對吧?
There's a party perfectly set for two months from now.
兩個月後正好有個合適的派對
Both Kiyoka and I are invited. As a first step, you should come with us.
我跟清霞都有受邀出席 作為第一步,妳也一起參加吧
You'll be fine. This party is like a friendly social gathering.
沒事的,這場派對 是不必那麼拘謹的聯歡會
B-But...
可是...
Why don't you give it a try?
妳就試著參加吧
Sir...
老爺
All your studying won't mean anything if you can't put your knowledge to use.
不管妳學得再多 不能付諸實踐就毫無意義了
I understand.
我明白了
Please let me go to the party.
請讓我出席派對吧
Don't put so much pressure on yourself.
用不著逞強
I won't suddenly make you wear a dress and dance.
我不會突然就叫妳穿禮服跳舞
Y-Yes.
我知道了
Your basic demeanor is already proper. You don't have to worry.
用不著擔心啦 基本的儀態舉止妳原本就做得很棒
Do you... think so?
是這樣啊?
Yes.
是啊
I'll make a timetable for your lessons by next time. Let's work together.
下次來之前我會先擬定學習課表 所以我們一起加油吧
Yes.
好的
Ms. Hazuki is kind.
葉月小姐真溫柔
I want to become a splendid lady
我好想成為
like Ms. Hazuki.
像葉月小姐般出色的淑女
I want to be a wife deserving of my husband.
我想變成配得上老爺的妻子
I sense supernatural abilities...
是異能的氣息
Miyo. I'm coming in.
美世,我要進去了!
Stop it...
住手啊
You'll be all right. It's all right now.
沒事的,已經沒事了
A nightmare again.
她又做惡夢了
The remnants of supernatural ability feel similar.
異能的殘渣和之前的很像
The barrier around the house doesn't seem broken.
家裡四周的結界也看不出有破損
It's unlikely that an outsider has come in.
也不是外來入侵者造成的
If interference by supernatural abilities was possible...
如果能透過異能進行干涉的話...
Usuba...
薄刃...
Put the barrier up again!
重新設置結界!
Pay close attention!
大家繃緊神經!
Major General Okaito.
大海渡閣下
Yes.
嗯
I'm sorry I'm late.
抱歉來遲了
I'm sorry to have interrupted your work, Kiyoka.
不好意思打斷你的工作,清霞
It's fine.
沒關係
I heard Takaihito has received a revelation.
聽說堯人大人接收到天啟
I'm having a meeting with him, I'll also report on Tatsuishi.
我現在要去晉見堯人大人 順便報告辰石家的事
I need you to come with me.
你也一起過來
Yes, sir.
好的
And before we go, there's something I have to tell you.
另外,前去晉見之前 有件事必須先告訴你
What is it?
請問是什麼事?
There was a tomb break-in.
盜墓者出現了
It can't be...
難道是...
It's true. We don't have the details yet,
沒錯,雖然還不清楚詳情
but the Grave was opened.
奧津城被打開了
The time has come.
時機已成熟
We're coming for you,
我會去迎接妳
Miyo.
美世
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Ohno
字幕翻譯:黃琳雅